## **Geoffrey Bergeret** French Nationality 27 years old

## DevOps Engineer

« Divide and Rule »

+44 7871 334653 job@gbergeret.com www.gbergeret.org

Profile

By experience, I acquired lots of skills in several area like: Software, System, Network or DevOps Culture. Now my goal is to focus on the DevOps way: "Develop your infrastructure as code and automate everything to make it smarter".

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 10/2017 to now

- Initiated GitOps principales from Infrastructure as Code (with Peer Review)
- Implement Jenkins Pipeline integration with terraform to run terraform from Jenkins
- Restructured Terraform projects integrate them with the CI/CD pipeline
- Integrate Ansible with our Terraform projects to manage OS provisioning
- Worked on AWS accounts segregation with AWS Organisation (workload segregation)
- Deployed gravitational teleport as SSH bastion
- Deployed and maintain transit VPC (with datapath.io solution) cross regions and VPCs

DevOps Engineer at Drivetribe – 11/2016 to 10/2017

- Infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (GitOps).
- Move platform to docker infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Refactoring environments to be easy to run, update and dispose (ga, staging, prod).
- Work around failure points and scalability to be online as much as possible.
- Improve, speed up and stabilise the releasing process.

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 04/2016 to 11/2016

- Move to infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (all in git).
- Move platform to micro-services infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Work around failure points to be as much as possible always online.

System and DevOps Engineer at Contentment – 10/2015 to 03/2016

- In charge of all System and DevOps part, sizing the infrastructure and support it.
- Migrate and automate the deployment of the existing architecture in AWS with Docker.

Network Engineer (Apprentice) at Orange SA – 09/2012 to 09/2015

- VPN production automation (B2B) by implementing scripts (in Perl).
- Network support (second line) for routing, QoS, LAN on border side.

**Education & Training** 

2015: Master of Science in Computer and Network Engineering (1st class) at ESIPE

Languages Skills

French -> Native

English —> Fluent (live in UK for almost 3 years)

Technical Skills

**DevOps**: Kubernetes, terraform, test-kitchen, GitOps, CI/CD (Jenkins)

System: Linux, Bash, Ansible, Python, Docker

Infrastructure: AWS, VPN, Kubernetes, Proxmox, Firewall (pfsense, ipables)

Networking: Routing (OSPF, BGP), VRRP, OpenVPN, DHCP, DNS Database: MERISE, ORM, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB Software Developpement: UML, Java, C/C++, Jekyll (Liquid), Git

Management Skills

Team organisation Conduct training Project Management Facilitate meeting Independent Seminar facilitator

Hobbies

Jogging **Fitness**  Motorcycle

Travelling Cooking Economy/Finance